### **HAMZAT** HABIBLLAHI ADEWALE

Plot 6/8 Araromi Igbehinadun Community, Road 1, Ajofeebo, Sanyo Area, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamzat-habibllahi-8b9542110

https://habibllahi.github.io/personal/ habibllahi3@gmail.com +234[0]8142408496

# **ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS**

### FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE ABEOKUTA (FUNAAB)

2015

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical and Electronics Engineering); second class upper.

### OLADIPO ALAYANDE SCHOOL OF SCIENCE

2009

West Africa Senior School Certificate.

### **SKILLS**

#### **Electrical**

- 1) Mini grid management
- 2) Electrical installation (conduit and surface).
- 3) Solar hybrid installation

# Software development

- 1) Programming languages: Kotlin and Java
- 2) Micro-service development using Java with spring framework, Tomcat server, Hibernate and MySQL database
- 3) Native Android mobile application development using Kotlin with Android Standard Developmental Kit
- 4) Cross platform desktop application development using Java with JavaFX framework

### **PRESENTATIONS**

Presentation: DESIGN OF INDUSTRIAL BASED TEMPERATURE AND HUMIDITY MONITORING SYSTEM USING EMBEDDED SYSTEM APPROACH FOR HEALTH AND SAFETY.

The Nigerian Universities Engineering Students' Association (NUESA) Conference. 2015. Nigeria.

# **COMMUNITY SERVICES**

# National Youth Service Corp (NYSC) teacher

2016 - 2017

Abonnema Girls School, Abonnema, Rivers state, Nigeria

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Rubitec Nigeria Limited, Lagos state, Nigeria

2019-Recent

Role: Utility Manager

Responsibilities:

- 1) Management of 85KWp solar mini-grid power generation, distribution and consumption
- 2) Monitoring and supervision of power sales
- 3) Sighting of viable communities for Rubitec solar min-grid development and data collection from such communities using Kobo collect tool.
- 4) Installation of solar powered DC system and AC coupled system

Freelance 2018 - 2019

Role: Junior software developer

Responsibilities:

Development of desktop software and embedded solutions.

Role: Embedded system developer

Responsibilities:

- 1) Design, development and simulation of analogue, digital and embedded system as a control solution.
- 2) Installation of a solar hybrid system as a sustainable and renewable electrical energy source for clients.
- Fundamental electronics trainer.

# HIC mikroLAB, Ogun state, Nigeria

2014-2015

Industrial attachment trainee.

Responsibility:

To technically participate in all indoor and outdoor works as a trainee.

Solar power development and installation trainee.

Electronics trainee.

### **ABOUT**

I am 2015 graduate of Electrical Engineering with tangible and continuous work experience in solar development and software development. I am a JVM programmer comfortable with Kotlin and Java programming languages. My software development skill is diverge on native android mobile development, cross platform desktop development and REST micro-services development. I have work experience in solar design, development and management.

### PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth: 29th January 1992, Nationality: Nigerian, State of Origin: Ogun State

Local Government Area: Abeokuta-South, Sex: Male

## **HOBBIES AND LEISURE INTERESTS**

• Watching technological audio visuals.

• Playing video games and watching movies on Netflix.

### MORE ABOUT ME

https://habibllahi.github.io/personal/